<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 13:25:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Do you have what it takes to apply to the Integration Fund and get your share of the $1 million?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/takes-apply-integration-fund-get-share-1-million/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/takes-apply-integration-fund-get-share-1-million/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaux Choplin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20760</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Still living with your parents? It’s time to pack up and apply to the Integration Fund! The launch of the $1 million Integration Fund marked the start of special efforts made on offering local modules to PrestaShop merchants on the Addons Marketplace. A few weeks later, 300+ applications have been received, 40+ modules are in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/takes-apply-integration-fund-get-share-1-million/">Do you have what it takes to apply to the Integration Fund and get your share of the $1 million?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Still living with your parents? It’s time to pack up and apply to the Integration Fund!</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/">launch</a> of the <strong>$1 million Integration Fund</strong> marked the start of special efforts made on offering local modules to PrestaShop merchants on the Addons Marketplace.</p>
<p>A few weeks later, <strong>300+</strong> applications have been received, <strong>40+</strong> modules are in the making, already or soon allowing e-shops on all continents to be more adapted than ever to their customers!</p>
<p>This is great news, and we are expecting <strong>a lot of additional local modules</strong> to offer a full catalogue to our merchants on PrestaShop Addons.</p>
<p><span id="more-20760"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #cc4357">Boost your imagination with these examples of modules selected by the Integration Fund</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20763" alt="EN-Ex" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/EN-Ex-1024x517.png" width="700" height="353" /></p>
<p><strong>Would you like to build one? Especially a regional payment gateway, shipping carrier, or marketplace connector?</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/integration-fund" target="_blank">Apply and convince us to select your idea!</a></p>
<p>Indeed, we will be happy to financially support you whether your module is already developed or is still just an idea. If you are selected, your project will get funded and will receive special visibility in the countries it targets.</p>
<p>The Integration Funds is looking for developers with a passion for ecommerce, who are experts of their local ecosystem and are willing to share this knowledge through module development in <span style="text-decoration: underline">order to provide merchants with be the best ecommerce solution in their region</span>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #cc4357">3 tips to help you submit your module to the Integration Fund like a pro</h2>
<p>These 3 pieces of advice will give you the best chances to be selected to the Integration Fund.</p>
<h4 style="color: #79c6e4">1. Focus on the relevant countries</h4>
<p>We’ll consider your module as local if it does not fit to merchants worldwide. You need to give us the precise country or the precise list of countries where your module will be applicable.</p>
<h4 style="color: #79c6e4">2. Pick the right category</h4>
<p>If your module is relevant for a limited number of countries, that also means it concerns a local issue for merchants, which should be one of the following:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20762" alt="EN-Cat" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/EN-Cat.png" width="1024" height="313" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #79c6e4">3. Let us get your idea</h4>
<p>Let’s discuss to see what local modules are worth developing! To do so, please submit your <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/integration-fund" target="_blank">form</a> in English or French only, otherwise we will not understand each other <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20765" alt="star_wars" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/10/star_wars.png" width="481" height="309" /></p>
<p>Do not forget that PrestaShop Community is counting more than 800,000 wonderful motivated members and it keeps growing every day! Your idea might be about to be submitted…</p>
<p>We are waiting for your ideas!</p>
<p>#1million4devs</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/takes-apply-integration-fund-get-share-1-million/">Do you have what it takes to apply to the Integration Fund and get your share of the $1 million?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/takes-apply-integration-fund-get-share-1-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to craft marketing emails that convert</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/craft-marketing-emails-convert/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/craft-marketing-emails-convert/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 13:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20731</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>We all get them &#8212; email newsletters. Whether you love the discounts they contain, or hate that they pile up like junk in your inbox, it’s safe to say that you’ve seen your fair share. Most people don’t give a second thought to how these emails are created, but as you start to draft your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/craft-marketing-emails-convert/">How to craft marketing emails that convert</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all get them &#8212; email newsletters. Whether you love the discounts they contain, or hate that they pile up like junk in your inbox, it’s safe to say that you’ve seen your fair share. Most people don’t give a second thought to how these emails are created, but as you start to draft your own email newsletters, you’ll find that there’s more to them than meets the eye. To help you launch your own awesome email marketing campaign, today we’re sharing some advice on how to craft marketing emails that convert.<br />
<span id="more-20731"></span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#319ea5">Newsletter Content</h2>
<p>Before you start writing anything, be it code or marketing content, the first step is to figure out what you want to say. Ask yourself, “What message do I want to convey to my customers?” Some examples include:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Shop our sale!</li>
<li>Check out today’s deals</li>
<li>Here are the new products for this season or holiday</li>
<li>New product launches</li>
<li>We’ll be at this appearance / event next</li>
<li>We have new partnerships</li>
<li>The latest industry news</li>
</ul>
<p>Regardless of the message, it’s important to know what you’re trying to say before you do anything else. Once you know what you want to say, you can draft the email content. Be sure to use a voice that resonates with your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">buyer’s persona</a>, but keep it short so you don&#8217;t lose your customer’s interest. The exact length of your content will be determined by your email design, but more on that later.</p>
<h2 style="color:#319ea5">Call to action (CTA)</h2>
<p>After you know what you want to tell your customer, figure out what you want the customer to do next. For example, if you’re announcing your next event, do you want customers to buy tickets, RSVP or simply share the news? </p>
<p>Clearly identifying what you want your customers to do will make it easier for you to guide them there. Once you do so, you ‘ll need to identify the landing page that will allow customers to complete that action. Continuing with our previous example, if you want customers to RSVP for your event, provide the link where they can do so.</p>
<p>Finally, create a CTA button that drives users to the link. The CTA should contain enticing text that encourages the reader to click. <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/30-call-action-verbs-online-store/">Verbs are a great start; check out this article</a> for some examples.</p>
<h2 style="color:#319ea5">Email subject lines</h2>
<p>Once you’ve put together the message and know what you want your customers to do, it’s time to work on getting customers to open your email. The subject line is the most important line of text you’ll write for each email, and it is also the shortest. The goal of the subject line is to entice readers to open the email while accurately describing what’s inside.</p>
<p>Keep track of the subject lines you use and review them over time to ensure you’re optimizing your subject lines for conversions. </p>
<h2 style="color:#319ea5">Newsletter design</h2>
<p>As we mentioned earlier, each email newsletter should have a great design. Create a basic template that you’ll use time and time again. The design should include your logo in the header and a footer at the bottom that has your contact info, social media buttons and most importantly, a link to unsubscribe from your emails. While you&#8217;re designing your template, remember that it should reflect not just this email’s message but your overall brand. This includes deciding on a color palette, and the types of headers and fonts you’ll use consistently.</p>
<p>The body of your email should contain the elements we’ve worked on already: the content and call to action button. It should also feature gorgeous product photos that appeal to the customer and make your email more clickable. You can choose to have just one message or supplement a main feature with other articles. If you choose to have more than 1 segment, make sure you highlight each with bold headlines.</p>
<p>For some examples from PrestaShop merchants, check out this article to see our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-10-ecommerce-newsletters-of-2014-from-prestashop-merchants/">favorite newsletters from in 2014</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color:#319ea5">Mobile-Compatible</h2>
<p>Another key factor to consider are your mobile customers. Be sure your content can be scaled down to a smartphone’s screen size. Most of today’s <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?id_category=0&amp;search_query=newsletter" target="_blank">email marketing tools</a> have this functionality already built into the software. For a complete list of industry solutions available for your region please refer to our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners">partner pages</a>. </p>
<p>Use images that are sized properly to cut down on loading time. Also, be sure to give the images a descriptive name, just in case they don’t appear onscreen; otherwise your customers might wonder what 2356450x.jpg refers to&#8230; </p>
<h2 style="color:#319ea5">Next Steps</h2>
<p>For more ideas, check out what your competitors or suppliers have used in their emails. Haven’t subscribed to emails yet? <a href="http://milled.com/" target="_blank">Milled</a> has a great collection of emails which you can filter by brand and category. To jump right in and get started here’s a recap of the steps: </p>
<ol>
<li>Decide on the message </li>
<li>Draft the content</li>
<li>Figure out your customer’s next steps</li>
<li>Create a call to action</li>
<li>Write a catchy subject line</li>
<li>Select an email marketing tool</li>
<ol style="margin-top:0">
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?id_category=0&amp;search_query=newsletter" target="_blank">via a Module</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners">via a 3rd party tool</a></li>
</ol>
<li>Design a great-looking newsletter</li>
<li>Send! </li>
</ol>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
Already have an email marketing campaign in place? Let us know which step is the most challenging for you. Don’t have an email marketing base yet? Check out guest blogger Steve Chou’s article on “<a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/gather-emails-online-store/">How to gather more emails for your online store.</a>”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/craft-marketing-emails-convert/">How to craft marketing emails that convert</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/craft-marketing-emails-convert/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Steps to packing and shipping more efficiently</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 13:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20728</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As a successful business owner, you’ll find that you never quite have enough time. Whether it’s making changes to your site, taking care of customers or just taking some time for yourself, there’s always more to be done. Today we’re helping you get back some of your time by showing you how to pack and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/">3 Steps to packing and shipping more efficiently</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a successful business owner, you’ll find that you never quite have enough time. Whether it’s making changes to your site, taking care of customers or just taking some time for yourself, there’s always more to be done. Today we’re helping you get back some of your time by showing you how to pack and ship more efficiently.<br />
<span id="more-20728"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">1. Identify bottlenecks</h2>
<p>The first step to improving any process is identifying bottlenecks. A bottleneck in this context refers to any activity that operates at a slower rate than all other activities in your operation. These slow-downs are generally easy to identify in warehouses because of the accumulation of orders that occur around  that operation. Depending on the complexity of your business activity, you may not have any bottlenecks or many! </p>
<p>If you don’t see any bottlenecks right away, try spending a few days observing how orders are processed. You’ll be able to spot any inconsistencies in the process that could use improving. If after a few days, you’re still unable to identify a specific bottleneck, consider ways to improve your entire operation instead. </p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">2. Refine the process</h2>
<p>If you have multiple bottlenecks, prioritize them from major to minor issues. You can choose to prioritize them by cost spent or time wasted. Organize it in the way that makes the most sense for your business. We’ll tackle the large issues first, because resolving larger issues may also clear up the smaller ones.</p>
<p>Find ways to remove the first bottleneck by improving the time it takes to complete the associated action or limiting the number of errors created. Ask yourself: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What part of this step isn’t necessary? What can I remove?</li>
<li>Can part of this step be completed later in the process?</li>
<li>Can part of this step be completed earlier in the process?</li>
<li>Can part of this step be combined with another task?</li>
<li>Is there a faster way to execute this task? </li>
<li>What additional resources can expedite this process?</li>
</ul>
<p>Keep this basic warehouse process in mind as we run through a couple of examples of how you can improve your business processes. </p>
<p><em>(1) Print packing lists → (2) pick orders → (3) print orders → (4) pack orders → (5) weigh package → (6) print shipping label → (7) off to the mailman</em></p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Removing a step</h4>
<p>If you’ve been with the company for a long time, this is generally the hardest solution to find. All tasks, even those that seem obvious to you, must be evaluated. For a new perspective, consider having a new trainee make these suggestions. </p>
<p>In the example listed above, consider the 1st task, print packing lists. If packing lists are not needed for your company, you can simply print orders forms and pack customer orders using that document. This cuts down on both the time and resources spent on printing the packing list. </p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Moving parts of a step</h4>
<p>There are some parts of your process that can be grouped with other tasks to maximize efficiency. Consider any action that takes away from the seamlessness of a process. For example, when  a product runs out while you’re packing orders, do you have to go and pull more inventory from storage? This is fine when you don’t run out of inventory, but if you run out of inventory multiple times during the day, it disrupts the flow of the process. Each time something runs out, the pack order process is paused so the inventory can be restocked.  </p>
<p>To make the order packing process more seamless, you create an inventory restocking process and move it the to the beginning of the day. It appears to add a new step to your overall process, but you’re simply defining a substep that is done regardless. By doing so, you clarify the overall process and make the order picking step more efficient. </p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Refining a step</h4>
<p>Sometimes it’s about improving upon a process that you already have in place. Sometimes you need to take a step back to see how you can make your process better. In our example, look at the “weigh package” step. If you already have the products on hand, you can weigh the product in advance and enter them in your PrestaShop store so that labels are automatically generated with the corresponding weights. This may not completely eliminate the “weigh package” step because you’re still weighing each product, but your order packing process is now more efficient. </p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Additional resources</h4>
<p>Your last resort improvement is to call upon additional resources. This option should be considered last because it is not only more expensive to implement, but it’s bit like cutting corners to improve your shop’s efficiency. However, once you’ve exhausted all your options, it can be the only improvement left to make. If you find that all the steps are running as efficiently as they can, yet you’re still not able to fulfill orders on time, consider hiring another employee to help with the overall shipping process. Additionally, you can acquire new tools to expedite specific tasks. This can be anything from purchasing better printers to expedite the printing to or new carts to expedite order picking. </p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">3. Measure</h2>
<p>Once you know what you want to improve in your shop and how you want to approach the task, it’s time to implement. However, to know how well the changes are or are not working, you have to put some type of measurement tool in place. For example, you can measure the amount of time each step takes to complete. Additionally, you can count the number of orders processed each day. Either way, be sure you have something to compare your old process’s effectiveness against the new. </p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">In a nutshell</h2>
<p>Improving your shop’s operations is a continual process. There’s always new technology or ideas that can help you improve the way your shop works. All you need is a little time, some patience and a drive to want to be better. To make your business more effective: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Define your bottleneck, or problem</li>
<li>Refine that process and make it better</li>
<li>Measure your changes</li>
<li>Repeat</li>
</ul>
<p>What changes do you plan on making to your shop before the crazy holiday season? Let us know in the comments below. Already made some changes? Share some of the results you’ve found. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/">3 Steps to packing and shipping more efficiently</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Free Online photo editing tools</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20676</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you sell online, your customers rely on images and text to make purchasing decisions. From product images and homepage banners to newsletter graphics, it’s important to have beautiful images that convince customers to convert. To help you get your images picture perfect, we’re sharing 7 free online photo editing tools. Online photo editing services [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/">7 Free Online photo editing tools</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you sell online, your customers rely on images and text to make purchasing decisions. From product images and homepage banners to newsletter graphics, it’s important to have beautiful images that convince customers to convert. To help you get your images picture perfect, we’re sharing 7 free online photo editing tools. Online photo editing services are great because you don’t need to download software. Additionally, you can access these services from any computer with an internet connection, which is perfect for entrepreneurs on the go.<br />
<span id="more-20676"></span></p>
<h2><a href="https://www.polarr.co/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">1. Polarr</a></h2>
<p>Polarr launched in 2014, making it one of the newest options available. It was founded by 2 Stanford students with a passion for art, photography and technology.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/1-polarr-1024x508.png" alt="1 polarr" width="700" height="347" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20678" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Endless color correction options.</strong> From basic features like saturation, temperature and tint, to expert functionalities like tonal curves and split toning.<br />
	<strong>- Guide to software features.</strong> With countless tools and features, it’s easy to get overwhelmed. They’ve got you covered with a <a href="https://www.polarr.co/guide" target="_blank">comprehensive guide</a> that includes examples and demos.<br />
	<strong>- Abundant photo presets.</strong> Pick from over 25 preconfigured photo edits fine-tuned to work with most images.<br />
	<strong>- Great for editing main images.</strong> The many options for adjusting color are perfect for editing banner images. The tools make it easy to give all your images a cohesive look that ties your online shop together visually.
</p>
<h2><a href="https://pixlr.com/editor/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">2. Pixlr</a></h2>
<p>Pixlr apps comes from Autodesk, the creator of Sketchbook, 123D, and Homestyler. The free version is supported by advertisements, but customers can opt for ad removal by paying $14.99 annually or $1.99 monthly. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/2-Pixlr-1024x611.png" alt="2 Pixlr" width="700" height="417" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20679" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left:30px">
	<strong>- Layers</strong> allow users to create composite images: you can merge two images into one or even give each of  your products a different background.<br />
	<strong>- Available in multiple languages</strong> including Spanish, French, German and Italian. This makes learning the function of each tool easier for non-English speakers.<br />
	<strong>- History option for undoing changes.</strong> Not happy with the changes you made? The history tab makes it easy to move back and forth between changes.<br />
	<strong>- Showcase.</strong> Each week, Pilxr sponsors a photo challenge. The best submissions are then featured on their showcase. It’s a great way to get your feet wet with photo editing, pick up new tricks and maybe even get your brand noticed.
</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.fotor.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">3. Fotor</a></h2>
<p>This powerful photo-editing suite comes with all the features you’d expect, like photo resizing and color correcting. However, this software is separated into 3 main functions &#8212; photo editor, collage creator and designer. To access premium designs and templates, simply create an account.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/3-fotor-1024x458.png" alt="3 fotor" width="700" height="313" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19385" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Great user onboarding</strong> makes it easy learn the features, so it’s super easy to get started.<br />
	<strong>- The collage function</strong> makes it easy to stitch together photos to make image compilations. If that’s not cool enough, you can easily add stickers to give your images more character.<br />
	<strong>- Social media templates</strong> help you create engaging pictures for your social media pages. Best of all they’re sized correctly so you never have to worry about whether your image will work on a specific platform.<br />
	<strong>- Their YouTube Channel</strong> provides walkthroughs that help you create images for your online shop. Check out their latest <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/">“Back to School”</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zajtO-LUO1Q" target="_blank">poster tutorial</a>.
</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">4. Canva</a></h2>
<p>Launched in Australia Canva raised over $3.6 million to launch a beta version in 2012. To date, they have close to 5 million users worldwide. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/4-Canva-1024x510.png" alt="4 Canva" width="700" height="348" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20681" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	- With over <strong>40 pre-made templates</strong>, you can design anything from social media headers and posts to invitations for all types of events.<br />
	<strong>- A <a href="https://designschool.canva.com/" target="_blank">Design school</a></strong> walks you through all types of design-related topics including infographic design, design layout and even color theory.<br />
	<strong>- 3rd party stock images</strong> are readily available for purchase, directly from the platform. This is perfect if you’re missing one last thing to complete your design.<br />
	<strong>- Frequent updates</strong> means you’ll get the latest design trends built in. If Facebook adds a new image size, you know you’ll have the template on the site soon.
</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.picmonkey.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">5. PicMonkey</a></h2>
<p>Love Picnik? You’ll love PicMonkey. After Google acquired and later disbanded Picnik, the founding team worked together to create this platform. It’s functionality includes photo editing, graphic design and collage making. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/5-PicMonkey-1024x500.png" alt="5 PicMonkey" width="700" height="341" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20682" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Great for beginners.</strong> Of all the platforms we mentioned, this is by far the simplest to use.<br />
	<strong>- Lots of pre-set filters</strong> make it easy for you to give all your pictures the same look and feel. Simply click on a filter to apply it, then use the new window to make slight adjustments.<br />
	<strong>- Lots of themes</strong> to pick from to add a little holiday spirit to your shop. Its perfect when you’re decorating your shop and interacting on social media.<br />
	<strong>- Collage option</strong> for stitching images together. It’s pefect if you’re compiling images, especially when you want to feature multiple images that are quite similar (like ones from an event.)
</p>
<p>To take advantage of their premium features, simply upgrade for either $4.99/month or $33/ year. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.ribbet.com/app/?picnik#/edit/basic" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">6. Ribbet</a></h2>
<p>When Google closed Picnik in 2012, the founding team set out to offer clients a comparable solution. They offer a free version of their service that users can easily upgrade to access more functionality. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/6-Ribbet-1024x457.png" alt="6 Ribbet" width="700" height="312" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20683" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Add your favorite features</strong> to a tab so you can easily access them each time you edit a picture.<br />
	<strong>- Edit pictures from your social media accounts</strong> without having to re-download them to your shop.<br />
	<strong>- Turn pictures into products</strong> with integrated sites like Zazzle and MILK. Directly upload your designs into the platforms to purchase custom mugs, shirts or even photo books.
</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.befunky.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">7. BeFunky</a></h2>
<p>Just like many of the tools mentioned in this blog, BeFunky offers a completely free version with the option to upgrade for $4.95/ month or $24.95/year. There are also sections for photo editing, collage making and design. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/7-BeFunky-1024x510.png" alt="7 BeFunky" width="700" height="348" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20677" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Specific tools</strong> for each function helps you narrow down the features you’ll need for each type of editing need. For example, the design tab gives you easy access to templates that are perfect for each social media platform.<br />
	<strong>- No ads and a minimized menu</strong> gives way to a large editing area so you have more screen space dedicated to photo editing.<br />
	<strong>- Mobile versions available.</strong> The software is not just available online; you can also download it from from the App store and Google Play.
</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Ready to revamp you shop? Upload the new images you’ve made. Not sure what the size requirements are? Check out this blog post for <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/">image size and types for PrestaShop’s</a> default template. Already using one or many of the free online editing software we listed? Let us know which is your favorite in the comments below. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/">7 Free Online photo editing tools</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to consider when choosing payment options</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camille Sila]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There are a million things to think about when you start a new online shop. You&#8217;ll probably spend a lot of time thinking about design, how your products or services are presented and how to attract traffic to your website. Additionally, you’ll be thinking about how to achieve a high conversion rate for your customers [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/">What to consider when choosing payment options</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are a million things to think about when you start a new online shop. You&#8217;ll probably spend a lot of time thinking about design, how your products or services are presented and how to attract traffic to your website. Additionally, you’ll be thinking about how to achieve a high conversion rate for your customers to check out or to register. You may also find it a challenge to select the right mix of payment options to offer to your customers – and your selection should take your customers&#8217; needs and the costs and level of security of each payment method into consideration.<br />
<span id="more-20640"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#ea5c2a">Various options for various requirements</h2>
<p>Studies show that around 88 percent of all potential buyers leave an online shop if the only payment option offered is advance payment. By integrating further payment methods, the purchase abandonment rate can be reduced to 1%. Successful online merchants predict that in the next five years PayPal, credit card (with and without 3-D Secure protection), and &#8220;payment through invoice&#8221; will gain further customer importance (ibi research, 2015, University of Regensburg). </p>
<p>Apart from customer acceptance, merchants also need to compare the direct costs of a payment method as well as potential indirect costs. For instance, the University of Regensburg found out that for &#8220;purchase on account&#8221; other costs increased the direct costs such as those from late payments, payment irregularities, defaults, and even encashment procedures. </p>
<p>Last but not least, security plays an important role in the payment method selection process: on the one hand merchants want to establish customer trust by protecting sensitive payment data (e.g. thanks to encryption), and on the other protect themselves by applying fraud prevention measures for each payment method.  </p>
<h2 style="color:#ea5c2a">Support from experienced Payment Service Providers</h2>
<p>Online businesses should spend their IT resources on their own products rather than dealing with online security requirements. They can rely on payment service providers who offer different options for accepting different payment methods. Startups, and small and medium-sized businesses can benefit from the know-how of payment service providers. To serve merchants with maximum security, providers should be PCI-certified (Payment Card Industry). </p>
<p>Because online shops are at risk of fraudulent behaviour, payment service providers usually apply additional fraud prevention measures. Automated risk checks and encryption of sensitive payment information help ensure online shops do not fall victim to fraudulent abuse, and reduce financial damages. </p>
<h2 style="color:#ea5c2a">About PAYMILL</h2>
<p>PAYMILL is a PCI-certified payment service provider which makes it easier for online businesses to process credit card payments. The <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/payment/paymill">free PAYMILL module</a> offers an easy way for integrating card payments into your PrestaShop. PrestaShop merchants receive the access data for the module by registering and activating a free PAYMILL account. Merchants benefit from a flexible technical solution which allows designing their own payment and which offers the optional usage of the 3-D secure protection feature (known as Verified by Visa or MasterCard SecureCode). All these features help merchants increasing their conversion rates. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/">What to consider when choosing payment options</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>9.5 ways to participate in the PrestaShop Community</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking for ways to participate in the PrestaShop community? Here are nine ideas! As you may know, we dedicated our new mascot, Preston the puffin, to our community. This little bird is not just resourceful, but survives by living in large communities. Read on to see how you can contribute your best skills to helping [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/">9.5 ways to participate in the PrestaShop Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for ways to participate in the PrestaShop community? Here are nine ideas! As you may know, we dedicated our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/preston/" target="_blank">new mascot, Preston</a> the puffin, to our community. This little bird is not just resourceful, but survives by living in large communities. Read on to see how you can contribute your best skills to helping the community thrive.<br />
<span id="more-20672"></span><br />
1. <strong><a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/PrestaShop" target="_blank">Code on GitHub</a></strong><br />
Speak PHP? Help add functionality or create a seamless user experience by contributing code on GitHub. Without the help of our contributors, we wouldn’t have a growing list of over 300 features &#8212; offered at no charge!</p>
<p>2. <strong><a href="https://crowdin.com/project/prestashop-official" target="_blank">Translate with CrowdIn</a></strong><br />
Speak a second language? Help us translate PrestaShop into your native language on CrowdIn. Not interested in writing copy? Vote on translations others have submitted. To date, our community members have already helped make PrestaShop available in: Bulgarian, Croatian, Dutch, Norwegian, Slovenian and Swedish.</p>
<p>3. <strong><a href="http://forge.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Forge</a></strong><br />
Have an idea for a software feature? Or have a bug you’d like to report? Search for and submit your request on our Forge. Each ticket is reviewed by a member of our team then prioritized.</p>
<p>4. <strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/forums/" target="_blank">Forum</a></strong><br />
The PrestaShop forum is one of the most active ecommerce communities around the world. With more than 800,000 members, conversations happen in a multitude of languages including English, French, Spanish and Italian.</p>
<p>5. <strong>Give us feedback on our documentation</strong><br />
On most pages of your PrestaShop Back Office, you’ll find a help section dedicated to helping you use that website. At the bottom of the help section, please leave us some feedback. This helps us understand what information is useful and what we need to add or remove.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Build themes</strong><br />
PrestaShop merchants are always on the lookout for the latest design trends for their website. If you like to create new designs, run the code through our <a href="https://validator.prestashop.com/auth/login" target="_blank">code validator</a>, then start selling them on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/content/25-how-to-sell-on-prestashop-addons" target="_blank">PrestaShop addons</a>, and watch your earnings roll in!</p>
<p>7. <strong>Build modules</strong><br />
Just like with themes, you can build your own modules with specific functions. Need help funding your project? We launched an integration fund dedicated to helping our community innovate and create modules that are adapted to each local market. Find out what we’re looking for, then <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/integration-fund" target="_blank">apply online</a>.</p>
<p>8. <strong>Join our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/club/" target="_blank">User Club</a>!</strong><br />
Want to share your experience and opinions with the PrestaShop product team? Join our User Club. Each month, we’ll send out a short survey to about an ecommerce-specific topic. In exchange, you’ll get sneak peeks about what’s coming up next.</p>
<p>9. <strong>Become a <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Ambassador</a> </strong><br />
Do you want to become a local representative for PrestaShop? We’re enlisting your help to host local meetups, give us product feedback, publish guest blog posts and more. Apply to be an Ambassador today. If selected, you’ll get our support and maybe even some swag.</p>
<p><strong>9.5</strong> Too busy running your online shop to actively participate? You are still part of our community. You read our blogs, share them on social, leave comments, subscribe to our newsletter and even follow us on social media. Regardless of how you choose to participate, we’re glad you’ve come along for the ride!<br />
____</p>
<p>Are you already playing a major role in our community today? Thank you for your contributions! Not an active member of our community yet? What are you waiting for? Join the largest international ecommerce community today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/">9.5 ways to participate in the PrestaShop Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to respond to customer feedback to boost your business</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 04:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20655</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Merchants that collect a lot of customer feedback and take the time to analyze it have most likely noticed that they often receive the same types of feedback over and over. In this article, discover 5 customer types and how to best respond to their feedback to put your best face forward and boost your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/">How to respond to customer feedback to boost your business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Merchants that collect a lot of customer feedback and take the time to analyze it have most likely noticed that they often receive the same types of feedback over and over. </p>
<p>In this article, discover 5 customer types and how to best respond to their feedback to put your best face forward and boost your business.<br />
<span id="more-20655"></span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Challenging.jpg" alt="Challenging" width="487" height="339" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20692" /></p>
<p><strong style="text-decoration:underline">Suggestion:</strong> Respond and thank the customer for their feedback, inviting them to contact the online retailer by email, and resend the email address. </p>
<p><strong>If you offer the customer a discount, it’s better to not do so publicly</strong> to avoid other customers from demanding the same. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Fan.jpg" alt="Fan" width="487" height="339" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20690" /></p>
<p><strong style="text-decoration:underline">Suggestion:</strong> it is important to <strong>make fans feel good</strong> by sincerely thanking them for their feedback with personalized messages.</p>
<p>As proof of the quality of their services, e-retailers can display this feedback on their online store.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Disappointed.jpg" alt="Disappointed" width="487" height="339" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20689" /></p>
<p><strong style="text-decoration:underline">Suggestion:</strong> <strong>do not ignore this type of feedback</strong>. Instead, thank the customer for doing business with your store and apologize for any disappointment or inconvenience. This will show that you have quality customer service. </p>
<p>For example, the problem might have been the delivery service, if the package did not arrive on time. But for the customer, your online store is responsible and its reputation is therefore at stake. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Busy.jpg" alt="Busy" width="487" height="339" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20691" /></p>
<p><strong style="text-decoration:underline">Suggestion:</strong> even if their feedback is short, the number of stars they gave impacts the e-merchant’s rating. <strong>Therefore, this type of feedback is very valuable</strong>. </p>
<p>Here, the e-retailer can show their appreciation for the time the busy customer spent writing a recommendation, without taking up more of their time. The e-retailer can respond, “Thanks! Have a great day!“</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/constructive.jpg" alt="constructive" width="484" height="627" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20688" /></p>
<p><strong style="text-decoration:underline">Suggestion:</strong> it is recommended to pay very close attention to the constructive customer’s feedback. <strong>Their suggestions for improvement are worth their weight in gold for online stores.</strong> Their feedback must be taken very seriously and online stores must improve the aspects mentioned. </p>
<p>Added bonus: <strong>Respond to their feedback by saying that their suggestion was used and invite them to go back to the e-store</strong>. <span style="font-style:italic">“Thank you for your feedback. We have now made it possible for the delivery address to be different from the billing address. We would love to welcome you back to our store! “</span></p>
<h4 style="color:#f89f45">About Trusted Shops</h4>
<p>The Trusted Shops solution helps retailers increase their sales figures by resolving their problems about trust in e-commerce. Trustbadge technology automatically collects real customer feedback, displays it in a personalized way on the website and increases their ranking in paid and free Google search results. Managing feedback conforms to NF Service procedures (AFNOR standard). The best retailers can obtain a trust mark from the European leader in e-commerce.  </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/">How to respond to customer feedback to boost your business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/respond-customer-feedback-boost-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 07:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20653</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the best features we added to PrestaShop v1.6 is the analytics dashboard. Not only is it one of the most appealing pages, it’s one of the most helpful when it comes to growing your business. Today we’ll break down the stats and share a few tips on how you can get the most [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/">Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the best features we added to PrestaShop v1.6 is the analytics dashboard. Not only is it one of the most appealing pages, it’s one of the most helpful when it comes to growing your business. Today we’ll break down the stats and share a few tips on how you can get the most out of them. Let’s get started!<br />
<span id="more-20653"></span></p>
<p>The first stats are often referred to collectively as KPI’s, or key performance indicators. Most companies use one or several of these statistics to evaluate their store’s overall performance compared to industry standards or past store performance.</p>
<h2 style="color: #86acc0">Dashboard</h2>
<p>The first chart you’ll see when you open your shop is your dashboard. Below we explain how each stat is calculated, what it tells you about your shop, and how the number can be skewed.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20664" alt="Bo" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Bo.gif" width="972" height="497" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Sales</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all order totals)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This number is pretty straightforward &#8211; it shows you how much money your shop is making. Hopefully, you’ll see an upward trend: in other words, your shop is making more money this month then it did the previous month. An upward trend shows your shop is growing and converting more customers, while a downward trend shows that customers are not purchasing as much or as often.</p>
<p>However, merchants generally see increases and decreases from month to month. The holiday sales season is a perfect example: strong holiday sales are often followed by a high number of returns.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Orders</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Number of orders received)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important to know the number of orders that your store receives, because it indicates the number of customers you are successfully converting. Ideally, you’d like to see an upward trend here, too. However, don’t be surprised if you find that this number dips during slower months. You can easily compare each month’s performance against numbers from the previous year to continually evaluate your store’s growth.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Cart Value</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sales / Orders)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Average cart value indicates the average amount that a customer spends on each visit to your site. <span style="text-decoration: underline">Cross-selling and upselling features have proven to effectively increase this number</span>. However, being too focused on increasing cart value can also hurt your shop. Be sure you’re promoting not just larger orders, but more orders. An increasing number of orders of increasing value is your ultimate goal.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Visits</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all traffic to your website)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Visits are a number game: the more people browsing your shop, the more likely you are to make a sale. Even when you don’t close a sale, your chances of converting that visitor one way or another, increase. <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/">Well-designed lead magnets</a> are a great way to engage your customers, even before they make the decision to purchase. However, a large number of visits can be attributed to “bots” scanning your website. The overstated number of visits can decrease other stats like conversion rates.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Conversion Rate</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of orders / sum of visitors)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Conversion rates give online merchants a good sense of how many visitors actually complete purchases. This metric is especially useful for merchants who are trying to optimize their website design. During A/B tests, conversion rates help merchants decide which final design should be used.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Net Profit Margin</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all revenue &#8211; sum of all expenses)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This statistic is one of the most important numbers online merchants should analyze. It clearly shows how much money your business has gained or lost. By filling in fields like wholesale price, bank charges and shipping fees, PrestaShop gives you an up-to-date estimation of your business’s financial standing.</p>
<h2 style="color: #86acc0">Products and Sales</h2>
<p>At the bottom of your dashboard page, you’ll find the product and sales table. It’s a quick summary of the information provided on your stats tab. We’ll detail what information each of the following tabs provides and how you can leverage that information.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20665" alt="product_sales" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/product_sales.gif" width="835" height="437" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Recent Orders</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This tab shows you the most recent orders placed on your website. It also details who made the purchase, the order size, and even the number of items purchased in the order. You’ll have a good idea of how busy or not busy, the business is. When you’re managing a team, it’ll help you decide how you should organize the staff and their responsibilities.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Best Sellers</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This tab simply shows you which products have been selling the best over the specified period of time. It’s worth noting if a specific image color or product category gets the most sales. Consider staging your images to mirror your best sellers or even purchasing more products that fall within the most-popular category.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Most Viewed</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This section simply lists the products that have been viewed the most by customers. Make sure you configure your back office to present the right numbers. Once you know which product is the most popular, match it against your best sellers list. Ideally the products should be similar. After all customers are more likely to purchase a product they’ve seen than one that they have not. If items on your most viewed list did not make the best seller list, consider adjusting the price to get customers to convert. Also keep in mind that a product’s merchandising may also play a role in how it’s viewed. For example, is the product currently listed on the homepage?</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Top Searches</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This table lists the top searches from customers browsing your website. It’s key to understanding what your customers are looking for when they visit your website. First, try searching each of these terms yourself to ensure they produce accurate results. If the search terms aren’t necessarily what you’re used to, consider adding them as “tag” to help customers find the product. Here are <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-essential-tips-to-improving-your-on-site-search-engine/">4 essential tips to improving your on-site search</a>.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>If you’re already using your PrestaShop back office dashboard, which stats do you refer to the most? Want to take a live tour of our dashboard? Check out the <a href="http://demo.prestashop.com/en/?view=back">PrestaShop demo</a>, then launch your own free <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/create-your-online-store">PrestaShop store</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/">Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays just around the corner, you’re probably trying to come up with a few easy ways to increase your average cart value and capture more holiday sales. Sometimes the solution can be super simple &#8211; as simple as improving the appearance of gift packages. Today we’re sharing 5 gift wrapping ideas to help [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/">5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays just around the corner, you’re probably trying to come up with a few easy ways to increase your average cart value and capture more holiday sales. Sometimes the solution can be super simple &#8211; as simple as improving the appearance of gift packages. Today we’re sharing 5 gift wrapping ideas to help boost your holiday sales!<br />
<span id="more-20645"></span><br />
The <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/12/wrappers-delight-a-brief-history-of-wrapping-paper/266599/" target="_blank">history of wrapping paper</a> spans the globe, from Japan, where furoshiki, reusable wrapping cloths have been used since the 17th century, to Victorian Britain where gifts were hidden with decorative paper, ribbons and lace. Wrapping gifts is a common practice around the world, and for online shops, it can easily be adopted to improve the customer experience and increase bottom lines. Customers purchasing gifts that will be shipped directly to the recipient appreciate the option. </p>
<p>Here are a few ways to make your gift wrapping options stand out. </p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">1) Personalized Note Card</h2>
<p>The first way to personalize an order is by including a card that shoppers can customize with a short message. Consider <a href="http://www.moo.com/us/products/greeting-cards.html" target="_blank">printing custom greeting cards</a> with your company’s logo and branding. Keep in mind that customers may celebrate different holidays than you do, so note card design should be festive but neutral. They’re simple to include in the order packing process because all you have to do is drop the card in the box!  Although you can choose to hand-write these notes, printing the text ensures readability and reduces errors.</p>
<p>This is a great option if this the is the first time you’ve thought about adding gift wrap. It’s relatively easy to implement  it doesn’t take too many supplies. To keep costs low, opt for a simple postcard without an envelope.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">2) Box with ribbon</h2>
<p>A box with a ribbon is a standard way to wrap a present. Just think of Tiffany’s iconic blue box and white bow <a href="http://www.tiffany.com/WorldOfTiffany/TiffanyStory/Legacy/BlueBox.aspx" target="_blank">Tiffany’s</a>. To include  this gift packing option, pick a box size that would fit a normal order. The order should fit snugly, so the gift doesn’t move around in transit. If your products come in a variety of sizes, consider having a few different boxes on hand. For a cute and custom design, <a href="http://us.selfpackaging.com/91-gift-boxes" target="_blank">PrestaShop store Self-Packaging</a> offers a large variety of gift packaging for all types of items.</p>
<p>Another key thing to consider is how you’ll add the gift wrap into your packing process. Consider pre-measuring the ribbon or dedicating one person to gift wrap so that your regular orders are processed consistently. Keep in mind that these gift boxes with a pretty bow should fit in your regular shipping box, making this option pricier to implement.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">3) Printed Gift Boxes</h2>
<p>Similar to a box with ribbon is a printed gift box, with one noteworthy difference: it doesn’t need to be shipped inside another box. <a href="http://www.uline.com/BL_5603/Apparel-Boxes" target="_blank">Uline offers a wide variety of pre-printed gift boxes</a>. This affordable option simplifies the packing process because all you have to do is replace the original box with the new decorated box. And just like with the note card, gift box design should be neutral to accommodate a wide variety of holidays.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">4) Decorative Mailers</h2>
<p>If repacking your order into boxes is out of your budget, you can opt to mail presents in prettily designed mailers. There are 2 types: <a href="http://www.scotchbrand.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/ScotchBrand/Scotch/Products/Catalog/~/Scotch-Plastic-Bubble-Mailer?N=4335+5584761+3294580325&amp;rt=rud" target="_blank">bubble mailers</a>, which are great for items easily damaged during transit, and self-sealing poly bags. Compared to the regular mailers, decorative mailers look more fun and festive. Mailers are even easier to use and implement than gift boxes and ribbons.</p>
<p>This same concept can also be applied to products shipped in large envelopes or sleeves. There are countless vendors that offer decorative versions of these shipping materials.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">5) Custom Tissue paper</h2>
<p>Another quick way to implement gift wrapping is to add <a href="http://www.uline.com/CustomStaticTissuePaper.htm" target="_blank">custom tissue paper</a>, which you can order in bulk and have customized with a color and your logo. You don’t have to make any changes to the shipping box; you’ll just slip some pretty tissue paper into your standard shipping box. If you want to upgrade the tissue paper, seal the tissue with a sticker that features your logo.</p>
<p>No matter which gift wrapping options you offer, it’s important to include a packing list &#8211; a document that details the order without listing prices. This makes it easy for the gift recipient to make exchanges or returns and for you to processes these orders.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Do you currently offering gift wrapping on your site? Tell us what worked best on your shop. Not yet offering gift wrapping? Share with us the options you’ll start offering. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/">5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Countdown to the holidays</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Summer is rolling to a close, which means another season is on it’s way: the holiday season. For retailers, it’s the start of the year’s busiest sale period. Many merchants are already knee-deep in their “Back-to-school” sales. If you’re still recovering from vacation, don’t worry: our countdown to the holidays will get you in shape [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/">Countdown to the holidays</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Summer is rolling to a close, which means another season is on it’s way: the holiday season. For retailers, it’s the start of the year’s busiest sale period. Many merchants are already knee-deep in their “Back-to-school” sales. If you’re still recovering from vacation, don’t worry: our countdown to the holidays will get you in shape for the 2015 holiday season.<br />
<span id="more-20632"></span><br />
You can choose to promote a sale during each of the holidays we mention below, or just the ones you personally celebrate. Either way, be sure you plan everything in advance so your sales smoothly and without a hitch!</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_september-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_september" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19342" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">September</h2>
<p><strong>Labor Day</strong> &#8211; (Sept 7th) Wrap up the summer season with a Labor Day Sale. This long weekend is the perfect opportunity to convert customers and clear out your summer inventory to make room in your warehouse for holiday shipments. </p>
<p><strong>Rosh Hashanah</strong> &#8211; (Sept 13th) This Jewish holiday celebrates a new year. Those who celebrate it often receive money rather than gifts, so consider offering gift cards for the occasion. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_october-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_october" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19341" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">October</h2>
<p><strong>Halloween</strong> &#8211; (Oct 31st) This eerie holiday may seem like it’s only for brave souls. However, merchants can also take advantage of Halloween, especially those that include costumes, candy and creepy decorations in their product catalogs. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_november-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_november" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19340" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">November</h2>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving</strong> &#8211; (Nov 26th) Turkey, gravy and sweet potato pie: nothing says Thanksgiving better than overindulging in food with those you hold dear. When all the food has settled and the football game is won, families get into the holiday spirit by decorating their homes for Christmas. </p>
<p><strong>Black Friday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 27th) A sale day that traditionally starts the morning of the Friday following Thanksgiving; however, as large retailers have become increasingly competitive, Black Friday sales have been starting earlier and earlier each year. <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/black-friday-store-hours-2014-2014-11" target="_blank">In 2014, some sales started as early as 5:00PM on Thanksgiving</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Small Business Saturday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 28th) Supported by the Small Business and Entrepreneurship Council, Small Business Saturday encourages people to #shopsmall. If you own a retail location, check out these four ways to prepare for <a href="https://www.sba.gov/blogs/5-ways-prepare-small-business-saturday" target="_blank">Small Business Saturday</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Cyber Monday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 30th) Cyber Monday is to online retailers what Black Friday is to brick and mortar retailers. Today is the day ecommerce websites display their best sales to get customers to buy gifts from them. Smaller retailers can choose to list a major Black Friday + Cyber Monday sale that runs throughout the entire weekend, or flash sales that encourage customers to shop at specific times. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_december-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_december" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19339" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">December</h2>
<p><strong>Hanukkah</strong> &#8211; (Dec 6th &#8211; Dec 14th) Although this is a religious holiday, today  it’s common to receive a either different gift on each or simply one large gift on the last day of this celebration. Gifts can range from the traditional items to unorthodox mainstream ones.  If you’re decorating your website, keep in mind that Hanukkah colors are blue and white.</p>
<p><strong>Christmas Day</strong> &#8211; (Dec 25th) For Christians and non-Christians alike, Christmas has evolved into a holiday that celebrates family. It’s a time for exchanging gifts among friends and family. </p>
<p><strong>New Year’s Eve</strong> &#8211; (Dec 31st) Every family welcomes the new year in its own way. Some throw parties that go on all night, while others prefer a quiet dinner with the family. New Year’s is not generally celebrated with gift giving but can be a great opportunity to promote products that celebrate a new beginning. </p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">Preparing for the holidays</h2>
<p>Now that you know which holidays you want to plan for, determine which types of sales you want to run. Select the products you want to feature. There are a couple common tactics such as seasonal goods, top sellers, gift-friendly products or even highest margin. </p>
<p>Once you’ve decided o n the products, it’s important to decide on how you want to promote them. For example, would you be using <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/">pop-ups or pop-ins to engage your customers</a>? Or would you send out <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/">email newsletters</a> to advertise your sale? Regardless of which method you select, be sure you have enough time to set up your back office. </p>
<p>Not sure what is the best option for your store? Contact any of our module advisors on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">Addons.PrestaShop.com</a>.  Already a seasoned pro? Share your tips below!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/">Countdown to the holidays</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
